Mohsen Hassani

Python Developer

Kerman

m.hassani.de@gmail.com

+98 938 491 8664

I'm a passionate web developer with more than 6 years of experience in software development and more than 3 years of experience in Python and Django.

I've developed many tools and websites using python for different clients in multiple countries and helped them grow their businesses.

Sponsorship required to work in the US

Work Experience

Software Development Consultant

Nakhll - Kerman 2021 to Present

After my success in Nakhll, I left that company to join a bigger one, but still, I am the Software Development Consultant of Nakhll company. I participate in their core development meetings and give advice to product owners and new developers.

Django Developer

STDev - Yerevan 2021 to Present

After leaving Nakhll as a full-time developer, I joined STDev, an international software development company based in Armenia with different clients around the world including the United States.

- I started with a project called GigaDebt.com, which was in its last months to release. One of my biggest tasks in that project was to migrate our client's data from their previous website, PracticePanther.com, to their new website after the release.
- after 4 months, I joined another project, CompensatoinTool.com which was under development for over 6 years. Some of my tasks in that project:
- 1. Create a Django module to parse string using Abstract Syntax Tree and convert them to Django's ORM system.
- 2. Connect the project to Tableau to generate powerful dashboards

Django Developer

Nakhll - Kerman 2020 to 2021

Working on a team of developers with Agile/Scrum methodology, I participate in developing a marketplace website (Nakhll.com).

- When I received the project, it was a mess with lots of bugs, which was done by some jr developers years ago.
- My first task in that company was to re-write some important modules and fix bugs in the website in order to survive in the market.
- 3 months after joining this company, I was promoted to lead backend developer company.

- We moved from Django templates to Django Rest Framework and Next.js. So I converted all views and forms to APIs and Serializers
- After 6 months, we started developing some new features for the website which helps the business to even grow in the market.
- I also created the Nakhll Documentation for my next developers in my last month in Nakhll.

Python/Django Developer

IPRPars - Kerman 2018 to 2020

Using Python, I developed these apps and websites:

- A keylogger app with the ability to gain shell access to the victim's system, transfer files and execute codes and payloads remotely. This app was able to connect to a specific server on the internet (in case the victim's system is connected to the internet) or listen to a port for any server inside a local network (for victims that are connected to a local network). This app helped the IPRPars company to get a national Penetration Test certification in Iran.
- A data migration app to migrate all data from different portals of the company's client (which was a university) during the Coronavirus pandemic in late 2020. This app helps the university's employees to transfer students' data from their main platform to the Canvas platform (https://www.instructure.com/canvas), create courses, and assign students to their courses in less than a minute, which usually took about a week or so to finish without this app.
- A Forex Journal website for one of the company's clients to keep track of their Forex trades, analysis them and even send them to different users using SMS or Discord, or Telegram.

C# Software Developer

FREELANCE - Kerman 2017 to 2018

I developed and learned a lot as a entry level of software engineer in university in this year

Network Engineer

Sirjan University of Technology - Sirjan 2016 to 2018

I was a member of the University's Network team to re-design and implement a 3-layer network at University. I gained many network experience in those 2 years:

- Network Basics (OSI, TCP/IP, IP Addressing, ...)
- Cisco Network
- Microsoft Windows Server basics
- MicroTik basics
- Basics of backup and replication using Veeam
- · Basics of network monitoring using OPManager
- · Basics of network security

Education

Bachelor in Software Engineering

Kerman

Skills

- Django (3 years)
- Git (4 years)
- REST (2 years)
- Python (3 years)
- JavaScript (2 years)
- Bootstrap (2 years)
- SQL (3 years)
- HTML5 (3 years)
- CSS (3 years)
- Agile
- Computer networking (4 years)
- Docker (1 year)
- Linux (3 years)
- Network security (2 years)

Languages

- Farsi Expert
- English Fluent

Links

https://github.com/mohsenone/

https://linkedin.com/in/mohsenone

https://stackoverflow.com/users/14272982/mohsen-hassani

Awards

Letter of Commendation from Sirjan University of Technology

2020

Letter of Commendation from IPRPars company

2020

Certifications and Licenses

LPIC-1

CCNA